

CONTACT INFO

Email: njruiz.nr@gmail.com Website: njruiz.github.io/cv-nruizjr LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/ruiznelson Address: Cebu, Philippines Contact: +63 995 766 2388

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Extensive knowledge in C# and Java programming languages
- Good amount of experience with .Net Framework (ASP, Win Forms, WPF)
- Knowledgeable in HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap 5, Typescript, Javascript, Angular, React Native
- Experience with **SOAP** and **WSDL** Web Services
- Experience using PostgreSQL,
 Firebird SQL, MS SQL, SQLite,
 Google Cloud Firebase

DEVELOPMENT TOOLS

- Professional development experience using Visual Studio, VS Code and Eclipse
- Experience with **Perforce** and **Git** version control tools
- Proficient use of Altassian JIRA bug tracking software
- Proficient use of Altassian Confluence, BOX, and MS Sharepoint and Office project management tools

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Flexible and strong analytical skills
- Ability to work under pressure and deliver quality output given the limited time
- Eager to learn new things
- · Keen with details
- Have a strong sense of responsibility and dedication

NELSON RUIZ JR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A goal-driven senior software engineer, capable of performing the software development life cycle in waterfall and agile methodologies. My professional experience in developing web, desktop and scripting applications ranges from requirements analysis up to deployment and project maintenance.

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR APPLICATION SYSTEMS ENGINEER/CONSULTANT

Fujitsu Philippines

SEPTEMBER 2022 - PRESENT

Role: Accountable for design and development of systems or applications based on client requirements

SOFTWARE ENGINEER III

Kyocera Document Solutions Development Philippines, Inc. APRIL 2016 - SEPTEMBER 2022

Role: Accountable for the development of management utility software applications for Kyocera multifunction printers

Key responsibilities:

- Lead developer for customization requests
- Lead developer for utility projects
- Senior developer for model support implementation
- Project estimation, Requirements and technical analysis
- Engineering testing
- Bug investigation and bug fixing
- Update functional and software requirement specifications
- for new supported features
- Train and mentor junior members of the team

Kyocera Net Viewer

A desktop application for managing network connected printing devices from a remote environment

• C#, WinForms .Net, Firebird SQL

Kyocera Net Admin

Web application for managing network and USB connected printing devices

• Java, Java EE, JSF, PostgreSQL, MS SQL

Kyocera Remote Work Assistant - Counter

Desktop application for retrieving print and scan count of USB and network connected devices

• C#, WinForms .Net

Kyocera KNA Agents Import/Export

Batch script to import/export network agents of Kyocera Net Admin

• Batch script, PostgreSQL

OTHER PROJECTS (FREELANCING)

JUNE 2021 - OCTOBER 2021

Chada Carwash Accounting Software

Desktop application to record all business transactions. Calculate profit/loss reports

• C#, WPF .Net, SQLite

CRMedicare

Mobile application for Health Insurance provider to manage customer profile and appointments

• React Native, Typescript, Google Cloud Firebase

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Cebu Institute of Technology - University | 2012 - 2016

- DOST Scholar
- PHIL-IT GCE Passer

HIGH SCHOOL

Minglanilla National Science High School | 2008 – 2012

GRADE SCHOOL

Minglanilla Special Science Elementary School | 2001 – 2008

• Special Science Class

HONORS AND ACHIEVEMENT

- DOST SEI RA 7687 Scholarship
- DOST SA CIT University Executive Public Information Officer
- 1 Approved application for Japanese Patent
- FY2021 Kyocera Philosophy Essay Writing Contest Awardee

CERTIFICATES

- PHIL IT General Certification Exam (2015)
- Udemy Course Complete Web Development Bootcamp (2022)
- Udemy Course ASP .Net Core and Angular (2022)

REFERENCES

Cherish Singcol

Technical Writer

Techtronics Inc.

+63 945 820 6831

Christian Laureano

Senior Systems Application Engineer / Consultant Fujitsu Philippines +63 905 278 2207

Ralph Martin Granados

Software Engineer III
KYOCERA Document Solutions Development Inc., Ph
+63 939 951 8905